Ujjanth Arhan

♠ Boston, MA **♦** (857) 313-2887

<u>arhan.u@northeastern.edu</u>

in linkedin.com/in/ujjanth-arhan

o github.com/ujjanth-arhan

Full stack web developer with 2 years of experience in a cross platform Ad-Aggregation Start Up. Reliable and proven capability in development, mentoring and management of people across teams. Experienced in creation of features from scratch, modification of existing ones with high level of interdependence for correct functionality including hotfixes, bugfixes and maintenance with close coordination with multiple teams.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University, Boston, MA (GPA 4.0)

Sep 2022 - May 2024

Master of Science in Software Engineering Systems

Courses: Concepts of Object Oriented Design, Data Science Engineering Methods and Tools

BNM Institute of Technology, Bangalore/Bengaluru, India

Aug 2016 - Aug 2020

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Science and Engineering

Courses: Object Oriented Concepts, Data Structures and Applications, Software Engineering, Computer Networks, Database Management Systems, Machine Learning, Cloud Technology and Applications, Internet of Things

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages and Databases Java, Python, C#, JavaScript, MySQL, MongoDB

Frameworks and Microservices VueJS (frontend), dotNet Core, ASP.net

Dev Ops and Maintenance Jenkins, Bitbucket, GitHub, Docker, Windows Server 2008

Miscellaneous HTML, CSS, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Jupyter Notebook,

Notepad++, Jira, Android Studio

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Associate Product Engineer, DeltaX, Bangalore/Bengaluru, India

Jul 2020 - Jun 2022

- Spearheaded creation of 'Financial Operations' in VueJS with server side rendering, pagination, multi attribute search, sort and manipulation of complex data structures increasing effectiveness of tracking by magnitudes
- Developed multiple microservices and utilities to perform email notification tasks, whatsapp notification tasks, data analyzer tasks, budget recommendation tasks increasing speed of existing ones by ~40%
- Implemented and modified agency wide end to end features involving front end, RESTful backend, middleware, data store and microservices using industry standards interacting with multiple other features
- Handled critical bug fixes across multiple features, resolution of support requests, server maintenance as part of miscellaneous tasks ensuring diminished downtime
- Lead and solo interviewer for position of Intern Associate Product Developer and involvement in training and induction of freshers ensuring they are comfortable working with technologies being used

Intern Associate Product Engineer, DeltaX, Bangalore/Bengaluru, India

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

- Created dashboard to show spends, adClicks, duration and other metrics of various line items at Campaign and adGroup level graphically with option to set amount and objective value decreasing clicks by about 15%
- Executed cost pacing feature using d3 charts depicting daily or monthly allocation of campaign money reducing heat map clicks recorded by about 10%
- Coordinated among multiple teams to deploy API, Web App fixes and patches reducing the downtime of the server by ~20% whilst moving the migrations to utilize the newer core framework instead of legacy framework

Intern Software Developer, NEC Technologies, Bangalore/Bengaluru, India

Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

- Led a team to build an inventory tracking system from requirement specification to deployment while handling display to support multiple screen resolutions and formats
- Trained 5 teams with methodology, tools and techniques ensuring effective implementation for projects being worked on